Amrendra Kumar

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

+91 9930109581 Email | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | AngelList | Portfolio

SUMMARY

I am a Full Stack Engineer with experience in Ruby and JavaScript libraries and frameworks. I am enthusiastic about writing clean, efficient, and accessible code. I am also committed to the total development lifecycle and providing high-quality code maintenance.

SKILLS

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Node JS, Express JS, MongoDB

Front-End: React, Redux, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

EXPERIENCE

HHAeXchange

Software Engineer, RoR Developer

Remote, India

June 2023 - Nov 2023

- Spearheading the enhancement of Adult Foster Care Home Base apps (used for fouty clients) to optimize home care solutions for HHAeXchange.
- Proactively addressing bugs and resolving tickets generated from scrum or client change requests.
- Proposed and developed unit tests using RSpec and Capybara for the existing codebase.
- Driving feature development using Ruby on Rails, leveraging common libraries, and conducting thorough testing with RSpec and Capybara.
- Collaborating closely with PM, QA, and other developers to streamline project workflows.
- Participated in ticket refinement, estimation, and process flow development.

ScaleUs Technologies

Remote, India

Jan 2023 - June 2023

Software Engineer, RoR Developer

- Features development with Ruby on Rails along with other common libraries and testing with RSpec
- Maintaining RESTful API to serve resources to the front-end developer.
- Features or bug development to solve tickets that arise from the scrum meetings
- Collaborating with various stakeholders including QA, PMs, FE and other BE Developers
- Implementation of Object-Oriented Programming with Design Patterns (MVC, ORM, and RESTful)

SME Globex

Remote, India

Software Engineer, Web Development

Oct 2020 - Jan 2023

- Implementation of Ruby on Rails, Node JS, React and Redux, Express JS, HTML5/CSS3, and maintaining RESTful API to serve resources to the front end.
- Features or bug development to solve tickets arising from the scrum meetings and product owner.
- Implementation of Object-Oriented Programming with Design Patterns (MVC, RESTful)
- Proposed back-end design and implementation with PostgreSQL, MongoDB, and open-source packages.
- Extensive project experience with Agile Development, Version Control (Git), and related tools.

AQM Technology

Mumbai, India

Test Engineer

Sep 2019 - Sep 2020

- Manage the Project Now 2.0 (Desktop, Web, and Mobile version) for the National Stock Exchange
- Led a team of seven Automation Engineers for Automation enhancements and Maintenance
- Automation testing using JAVA, and Selenium as a technology.
- Regular meetings with clients to discuss the project status, setting up and understanding client expectations to achieve the goals.

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Full Stack Web Developer

Remote Feb 2022 – Present

<u>Cars App</u> —This capstone React-Rails project allows users to book a test drive appointment.

• Built with: (Rails, Ruby, React JS, Redux, CSS, and HTML).

Budget App — This capstone project is about a mobile web application that allows to manage their budget.

Built with: (Rails, Embedded Ruby, and CSS).

Financial Metrics — This capstone project is about building a mobile web application to check a list of metrics.

• Built with: (React JS, Redux, External API, JavaScript, CSS, and HTML).

Math Magicians — It is a website for making simple calculations. It also reads a random math-related quote.

Built with: (React JS, JavaScript, CSS, and HTML)

MICROVERSE Mentor (Volunteer)

Remote, USA March 2022 – Nov 2022

- Mentored junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE Feb, 2022 – Sep 2022

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full-Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

IIMC, Kolkata, India Jan 2009 - Feb 2010

EPAF, Applied Finance

- Completed Executive Program in Applied Finance from Indian Institute of Management, Calcutta
- Developed an analytical bent of mind related to investment and trading in the Capital Market.

IGNOU, New Delhi, India

Jan 2000 - Dec 2003

BCA, Computer Programming

- JAVA, C++, C, Data Structures, Software Engineering, SAAD, Visual Basic, RDBMS (MySQL, ORACLE)
- Did project on Pension Management at SBI Jadugoda branch, Jharkhand, India in Visual Basic as front end and Oracle as backend database.
- Grade: B with 63%